Inventory of the Robert Hoppe papers, 1937-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert Hoppe papers,
1904, 1937-1946
(Bulk, 1937-1946)
2010C43
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Correspondence with family and friends, and personal documents, relating to German military activities on the Eastern and Western fronts during World War II.
Hoppe, Robert, 1915-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Sergeant major, German army.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence with family and friends, and personal documents, relating to German military activities on the Eastern and Western fronts during World War II.
Germany. Heer.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Eastern Front.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western Front.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.
- Correspondence Received, 1937-1944
  - Paul and Irene Hoppe, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Alois and Magda Hoppe, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Magda Hoppe, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Robert Scholz, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Paul and Uwe Emke, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Paul Emke, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Ditha Blöker-Emke, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Dreissen Family, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Robert Rosenberger, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Christa Schein, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Otto Rainer, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - General correspondence, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Eva Hoppe (neé Stapf) Correspondence, 1944-1945
    - March 1944 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - April, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - May, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - June, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - September, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - October, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - November, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - December, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - January, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - March, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- Correspondence Sent, 1944-1945
  - Eva Hoppe (neé Stapf)
    - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - March, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - April, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - May, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - June, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - September, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - October, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - November, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - December, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 7-8)
    - January, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 8-9)
    - February, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - March, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Identification materials, newspaper clippings, ephemera, 1904, 1937-1946; (Bulk, 1937-1946) (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Correspondence from Eva Hoppe (neé Stapf) to parents, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- General correspondence to Eva Hoppe, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- Corresondence from Franz Stapf to Eva Hoppe, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 13)